Guide to the David Trinidad Papers ca. 1970-2002 MSS.106
Fales Library and Special Collections
David Trinidad Papers
ca. 1970-2002
Fales Library and Special Collections
Trinidad, David, 1953-
MSS.106
54.5 Linear Feet (45 boxes)
Born in California in 1953, David Trinidad is a poet and teacher. He studied under Ann Stanford, Allen Ginsberg and Joan Larkin, and early in his career, he was the editor and publisher of Sherwood Press which published titles by such poets as: Dennis Cooper, Amy Gerstler, Tim Dlugos, and Alice Notley. Trinidad's own books of poems include: Pavane (1981); Monday, Monday (1985); Living Doll (1986); November (1987); Three Stories (1988); A Taste of Honey, with Bob Flanagan (1990); Answer Song (1994); Plasticville, (2000). He has been associated with the Beyond Baroque Literary/Arts Center in Venice, California and has an M.F.A. in Poetry from Brooklyn College. Currently Director of the Graduate Poetry Program at Columbia College in Chicago, he was previously on the Core Faculty of the M.F.A. Program at the New School in Manhattan. He has also taught at Princeton, Rutgers, and Antioch (Los Angeles).
Provenance
The David Trinidad Papers were purchased from Trinidad in July of 2000. The initial organization of the collection was established by Trinidad as he packed the materials for shipment.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note:
David Trinidad was born in Los Angeles in 1953 and raised in the San Fernando Valley. He received his B.A. in English from California State University, Northridge, where he studied poetry. From 1981 to 1984, he was the editor and publisher of Sherwood Press, established in memory of the poet Rachel Sherwood, which published titles by such poets as Dennis Cooper, Amy Gerstler, Tim Dlugos, and Alice Notley. Trinidad's first book of poems, 'Pavane,' was published in 1981. It was followed by 'Monday, Monday' in 1985, 'Living Doll' in 1986, and November, published by Hanuman Books in 1987. In the early eighties, he was associated with the writers who frequented Beyond Baroque Literary/Arts Center in Venice, California. This group included Dennis Cooper, Amy Gerstler, Benjamin Weissman, Jack Skelley, and Bob Flanagan. In 1988, Trinidad moved to New York City. That year another Hanuman Book, 'Three Stories,' was published. He received an M.F.A. in Poetry from Brooklyn College two years later. While at Brooklyn College, he studied with Allen Ginsberg and Joan Larkin. A Taste of Honey, Trinidad's collaboration with Bob Flanagan, appeared in 1990. It was followed by Hand Over Heart: Poems 1981-1988 (Amethyst Press, 1991) and Answer Song (High Risk Books, 1994). In 1996, he edited Powerless, the selected poems of Tim Dlugos. His most recent collection, 'Plasticville,' was published by Turtle Point Press in 2000. Trinidad has received grants from The Fund for Poetry and the New York Foundation for the Arts. He continues to live in New York City. He currently teaches poetry at Rutgers University, where he directs the Writers at Rutgers series, and is a member of the core faculty in the M.F.A. writing program at The New School. He has also taught at Princeton University.
Bibliography:
PAVANE. Chatsworth, CA: Sherwood Press, 1981.
MONDAY, MONDAY. Los Angeles: Cold Calm Press, 1985.
LIVING DOLL. Los Angeles: Illuminati, 1986.
NOVEMBER. New York: Hanuman Books, 1987.
PAVANE (revised edition). Los Angeles: Illuminati, 1988.
THREE STORIES. New York: Hanuman Books, 1988.
A TASTE OF HONEY (with Bob Flanagan). Los Angeles: Cold Calm Press, 1990.
HAND OVER HEART: POEMS 1981-1988. New York: Amethyst Press, 1991.
ANSWER SONG. New York: High Risk Books, 1994.
POWERLESS: SELECTED POEMS 1973-1990 by Tim Dlugos (editor). New York: High Risk Books, 1996.
ESSAY WITH MOVEABLE PARTS. Normal: Thorngate Road, 1998.
Scope and Content Note
The David Trinidad Papers is a part of the Downtown Collection at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing nearly 200,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel. The Downtown Collection, of which the Trinidad Papers is a part, is a comprehensive collection of printed materials, archives, and other materials related to the Downtown New York scene from ca. 1975 to the present.
The David Trinidad Papers is comprised of the correspondence and manuscripts of many notable literary and cultural figures, scrapbooks, manuscripts, collaborative projects, journals, journalism, reviews, business/production files for each book project, posters and videocassettes. The archive contains an almost comprehensive collection of the early to present-day literary career of David Trinidad. Trinidad's original organization of his papers was preserved as much as possible.
SERIES DESCRIPTION
Series I: Correspondence
Missing Title
Series I subseries A contains over 4 boxes of general correspondence.
Series I subseries B contains 7 folders of correspondence from family members.
Series I subseries C contains 2 folders of correspondence, fliers, permission forms, etc., regarding publications.
Series I subseries D contains 3 folders of miscellaneous correspondence including that of A.A. friends and students.
Series II: Writing
Missing Title
Series II subseries A contains 7 folders of manuscripts, contracts and cover designs for Pavane, Hand over Heart, and Answer Song.
Series II subseries B contains approximately 1 box of poetry worksheets from 1971 to 1997.
Series II subseries C contains 1 folder of collaborations with Dennis Cooper, Tim Dlugos, Amy Gerstler, and others.
Series II subseries D contains 17 folders of book reviews by Trinidad dating from 1990-1996.
Series II subseries E contains 3 folders of interviews with Dennis Cooper, Adrienne Rich and Patti Smith.
Series II subseries F contains 2 folders of essays.
Series II subseries G contains 7 folders of miscellaneous writing such as introductions and editor's notes.
Series II subseries H contains 1 folder of blurbs.
Series III: Publications
Missing Title
Series III subseries A contains Trinidad's books which have all been removed to the Downtown Collection.
Series III subseries B contains anthologies including Trinidad's poems, all but one of which have been removed to the Downtown Collection.
Series III subseries C contains magazines including Trinidad's poems, many of which have been removed to the Downtown Collection.
Series III subseries D contains Trinidad's poems translated into other languages, all but two of which have been removed to the Downtown Collection.
Series IV: Miscellaneous
Missing Title
Series IV subseries A contains 11 folders of reviews of Trinidad's books, plus 4 folders containing interviews with, articles about, and mentions of Trinidad.
Series IV subseries B contains articles and books in which Trinidad is mentioned.
Series IV subseries C contains 1 folder of poems dedicated to Trinidad by Dennis Cooper, Elaine Equi, James Schuyler, and others.
Series IV subseries D contains 1 folder of works in which Trinidad appears, by Tim Dlugos, Bob Flanagan, Allen Ginsberg, and others.
Series IV subseries E contains 12 folders of notices for Trinidad's readings from 1978 to 1998.
Series IV subseries F contains 26 folders of material related to Trinidad's teaching work with Beyond Baroque, Rutgers University, the New School, and others.
Series IV subseries G contains 19 folders of miscellaneous materials such as Sherwood Press books, resume, college diplomas, etc.
Series IV subseries H contains 15 notebooks covering February 1984 to August 1998.
Series IV subseries I contains Trinidad's date books from 1987 to 1998.
Series IV subseries J contains 2 folders of slides and photographs.
Series IV subseries K contains 4 videocassettes.
Series IV subseries L contains one LP which was removed to Oversize.
Series IV subseries M contains 7 folders of material from Trinidad's childhood.
Series IV subseries N contains 2 boxes of flat and oversize material.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged both alphabetically by subject/author heading and chronologically depending on the nature of the series. Descriptions occasionally extend to the item level.
The files are grouped into 4 series and subdivided into subject-based subseries.
Missing Title
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Writing
Series III: Publications
Series IV: Miscellaneous
Accretions 2002, Series I: Correspondence
Accretions 2002, Series II: Writing
Accretions 2002, Series IV: Miscellaneous
Accretions 2002, Oversize Materials
Related Material at the Fales Library and Special Collections
Serpent's Tail/High Risk Archive (MSS.086)
Tim Dlugos Papers (MSS.087)
Dennis Cooper Papers (MSS.085)
Downtown Collection (https://guides.nyu.edu/downtown-collection)
Separated Material
Monographs and periodicals accessioned with this collection were separated and cataloged individually into the Downtown periodicals collection. These materials may be accessed through Bobcat.
Books by David Trinidad
Missing Title
PAVANE. Sherwood Press, 1981.
MONDAY,MONDAY. Cold Calm Press, 1985.
LIVING DOLL. Illuminati, 1986.
NOVEMBER. Hanuman Books, 1987.
PAVANE (revised edition). Illuminati, 1988.
THREE STORIES. Hanuman Books, 1988.
A TASTE OF HONEY (with Bob Flanagan). Cold Calm Press, 1990.
HAND OVER HEART: POEMS 1981-1988. Amethyst Press, 1991.
ANSWER SONG. High Risk Books, 1994.
POWERLESS: SELECTED POEMS 1973-1990 by Tim Dlugos (editor). High Risk Books, 1996.
ESSAY WITH MOVEABLE PARTS. Thorngate Road, 1998.
Books by Other Authors
Missing Title
Dlugos, Tim. A FAST LIFE. Sherwood Press, 1982.
Gerstler, Amy. CHRISTY'S ALPINE INN. Sherwood Press, 1982.
James, David E. POWER MISSES: ESSAYS ACROSS (UN)POPULAR CULTURE. Verso, 1996.
Kaplan, E. Ann.POSTMODERNISM AND ITS DISCONTENTS: THEORIES, PRACTICES. Verso, 1988.
Lehman, David. THE BIG QUESTION. University of Michigan Press, 1995.
Lehman, David. THE LAST AVANT-GARDE. Doubleday, 1998.
Notley, Alice. SORRENTO. Sherwood Press, 1984.
Rasula, Jed. THE AMERICAN POETRY WAX MUSEUM. National Council of Teachers of English, 1996.
Rich, Adrienne. WHAT IS FOUND THERE: NOTEBOOKS ON POETRY AND POLITICS. Norton, 1993.
Sherwood, Rachel. MYSTERIES OF AFTERNOON AND EVENING. Sherwood Press, 1981.
Anthologies
Missing Title
POETRY LOVES POETRY: AN ANTHOLOGY OF LOS ANGELES POETS. Edited by Bill Mohr. Momentum Press, 1985.
AMERICAN POETRY SINCE 1970: UP LATE. Edited by Andrei Codrescu. Four Walls Eight Windows, 1987.
THE BEST FICTION AND POETRY FROM CSUN 1962-1988. Edited by Warren Wedin. Northridge Review Press, 1988.
AN EAR TO THE GROUND: AN ANTHOLOGY OF CONTEMPORARY AMERICAN POETRY. Edited by Marie Harris and Kathleen Aguero. University of Georgia Press, 1989.
POETS FOR LIFE: 76 POETS RESPOND TO AIDS. Edited by Michael Klein. Crown, 1989.
UNDER 35: THE NEW GENERATION OF AMERICAN POETS. Edited by Nicholas Christopher. Anchor/Doubleday, 1989.
BROADWAY 2: A POETS AND PAINTERS ANTHOLOGY. Edited by James Schuyler and Charles North. Hanging Loose Press, 1989.
OUT OF THIS WORLD: AN ANTHOLOGY OF WRITING FROM THE POETRY PROJECT AT ST. MARK'S CHURCH IN THE BOWERY. Edited by Anne Waldman. Harmony Books, 1991.
HIGH RISK: AN ANTHOLOGY OF FORBIDDEN WRITINGS. Edited by Amy Scholder and Ira Silverberg. Dutton, 1991.
THE BEST AMERICAN POETRY 1991. Edited by Mark Strand. Scribner's, 1991.
THAT VARIOUS FIELD FOR JAMES SCHUYLER. Edited by William Corbett and Geoffrey Young. The Figures, 1991.
MEN OF OUR TIME: AN ANTHOLOGY OF MALE POETRY IN CONTEMPORARY AMERICA. Edited by Fred Moramarco and Al Zolynas. University of Georgia Press, 1992.
A NEW GEOGRAPHY OF POETS. Edited by Edward Field, Gerald Locklin and Charles Stetler. University of Arkansas Press, 1992.
DISCONTENTS: NEW QUEER WRITERS. Edited by Dennis Cooper. Amethyst Press, 1992.
MONDO BARBIE. Edited by Lucinda Ebersole and Richard Peabody. St. Martin's Press, 1993.
WALK ON THE WILD SIDE: URBAN AMERICAN POETRY SINCE 1975. Edited by Nicholas Christopher. Scribner's, 1994.
SWEET NOTHINGS: AN ANTHOLOGY OF ROCK AND ROLL IN AMERICAN POETRY. Edited by Jim Elledge. Indiana University Press, 1994.
POSTMODERN AMERICAN POETRY: A NORTON ANTHOLOGY. Edited by Paul Hoover. Norton, 1994.
STAND UP POETRY: THE ANTHOLOGY. Edited by Charles Webb. The University Press, 1994.
THE NAME OF LOVE: CLASSIC GAY LOVE POEMS. Edited by Michael Lassell. St. Martin's Press, 1995.
THE BAD BOY BOOK OF EROTIC POETRY. Edited by David Laurents. Masquerade Books, 1995.
MONDO MARILYN. Edited by Lucinda Ebersole and Richard Peabody. St. Martin's Press, 1995.
PLUSH: SELECTED POEMS. Edited by Lynn Crosbie and Michael Holmes. Coach House Press, 1995.
SELECTED POETRY FROM THE BEST OF THE INDEPENDENT PRESSES. Consortium Book Sales, ca. 1995.
EXACT CHANGE YEARBOOK. Edited by Peter Gizzi. Exact Change, 1995.
EROS IN BOYS TOWN: CONTEMPORARY GAY POEMS ABOUT SEX. Edited by Michael Lassell. Crown, 1996.
LIGHTS, CAMERA, POETRY! AMERICAN MOVIE POEMS, THE FIRST HUNDRED YEARS. Edited by Jason Shinder. Harcourt Brace, 1996.
AMERICAN POETS SAY GOODBYE TO THE 20TH CENTURY. Edited by Andrei Codrescu and Laura Rosenthal. Four Walls Eight Windows, 1996.
QUEER DOG: HOMO-PUP-POETRY. Edited by Gerry Gomez Pearlberg. Cleis Press, 1997.
Magazines
Missing Title
AMERICAN LETTERS AND COMMENTARY. No. 8, 1996; No. 10, 1998.
AMPUTATED FINGERS. 1980.
ANGEL'S FLIGHT, Vol. 1, No. 1, January 1976; Vol. 2, No. 1, winter 1977; Vol. 3, No. 2, summer 1978; Vol. 4, No. 1, spring 1979.
ANTENNA. Winter 1979; Summer 1980.
AVENU. Vol. 18, No. 3, winter 1989.
B CITY. No. 2, spring 1985; No. 3, spring 1986; No. 4, spring 1987; No. 5, spring 1988; No. 6, fall 1989; No. 7, fall 1992; No. 8. 1993; No. 10; fall 1995.
BACHY. No. 18, 1981.
THE BAFFLER. No. 6, 1995; No. 7, 1995
BARNEY. No. 1-4 (1981-1984).
BATHOS JOURNAL. No. 1, fall 1997.
BEYOND BAROQUE 792. Vol. 10, No. 2, summer 1979.
BOMB. Winter 1991.
BOOMERANG! No. 4, summer 1998.
BROOKLYN REVIEW. No. 6, 1989; No. 7, 1990; No. 8, 1991; No. 9, 1992; No. 12, 1995.
CHELSEA. No. 55, 1993.
CHIRON REVIEW. Vol. 11, No. 4, winter 1992.
CITY LIGHTS REVIEW. No. 4, 1990.
COLUMBIA. No. 14, 1989; 1993.
COLUMBIA POETRY REVIEW. No. 8, 1995.
CUPS. September 1994.
CUZ. No. 3, 1989.
DEAR WORLD. 1991.
ENCLITIC. Vol. 10, No. 1, 1988.
EQUAL TIME. Issue 188, June 21, 1989.
FOREHEAD. No. 1, 1987.
GARGOYLE. Numbers 39 and 40, 1997.
GAS. Winter 1990.
GERBIL. No. 5, winter 1996; No. 9, 1998.
THE JACARANDA REVIEW. Vol. 3, No. 2, fall/winter 1988.
JOURNAL: A CONTEMPORARY ART MAGAZINE. Vol. 5, No. 45; fall 1986.
JOURNAL OF HOMOSEXUALITY. Vol. 34, No. 3/4, 1998.
L.A. WEEKLY. August 22-28, 1986; April 3-9, 1987; June 24-30, 1988.
LEMON FINGERS EMERGE. No. 4, 1987.
LIFE STORIES. No. 1, 1989.
LITTLE CAESAR. No. 11; 1980.
MAGAZINE. Vol. 13, No. 1, winter 1983; Vol. 14, No. 4, winter 1984.
MIRAGE. No. 2; 1986.
NEW AMERICAN WRITING. No. 5, 1989; Numbers 8 & 9, fall 1991.
NEW OBSERVATIONS. No. 87, 1992.
NO APOLOGIES. No. 5, 1985.
NO ROSES REVIEW. Vol. 1, No. 1, winter 1992.
NUDE ERECTIONS. No. 2, 1985.
OINK! No. 19, 1985.
THE PARIS REVIEW. No. 99, spring 1986; No. 106, spring 1988.
PEQUOD. Numbers 28/29/30, 1989.
THE POETRY PROJECT NEWSLETTER. No. 141, 1991; No.146, 1992.
POME. No. 3, 1989.
RIVERRUN. Spring 1992.
SANTA MONICA REVIEW. Vol. 1, No. 1, fall 1988; Vol. 2, No. 1, fall 1989.
SHINY. No. 5, 1990; Numbers 7 and 8, 1992.
SHINY INTERNATIONAL. No. 2, 1987; No. 3, 1987.
SOUP. No. 2, 1981.
SNAP. Vol. 1, No. 1, winter 1982.
ST. MARK'S POETRY PROJECT NEWSLETTER. No. 95, January 1983; No. 99, May 1983; No. 109, November 1984.
TORSO. Vol. 12, No. 12, July 1995.
THE WORLD. No. 46, 1993.
Translated Works
Missing Title
Japan HIGH RISK: AN ANTHOLOGY OF FORBIDDEN WRITINGS. 1991
Romania STEAUA 1992.
Czechoslovakia REVOLVER REVUE 1993.
Romania TRIBUNA 1993.
Romania TRIBUNA 1996.
Accretions 2002
Missing Title
The American Poetry Review. no. 1, vol 29, January/February 2000.
The American Poetry Review vol. 31 no. 4, July/Auguest 2002.
The Anthologies: The Literary and Fine Arts Mabazine of Rutgers College. vol. LXX, no. 1, Fall 1998.
The Barbie Chronicles. Ed. Yona Zeldis McDonough. New York: Touchstone, 1999. Poem: "Of Mere Plastic."
Bathos. no. 2, 1998-99.
"Begin Transmission: 13 Ghosts" by Bob Flanagan and David Trinidad. Ignition no.1, Fall 2000.
Beyond Polarities: A Handbook on Queer Issues. 1999. Poem: "Delphi."
Blood and Tears: Poems for Matthew Shepherd. Ed. Scott Gibson. New York City: Painted Leaf Press, 1999. Poem: "Pavane."
Boomerang! no. 5, Winter 1998
Boomerang! no. 6, Spring 1999.
Boomerang! no. 7 Summer 1999.
Boomerang! no. 10, Winter 2001. "From Phoebe 2002: An Essay."
Chain Chain Chain. by Jeffery Conway, Lynn Crosbie, and David Trinidad. Brooklyn: Ignition, 2000. Series of 26 signed.
Cooper, Dennis. All Ears: Cultural Criticism, Essays and Obituaries. New York: Soft Skull Press, 1999
Courier. No. 1, 2002. Ed. David Trinidad. P 55. Chicago: Columbia College, May 2002.
Crossroads. no. 57, Sutumn 2001.
Crux. 4:1, 26 October 2001.
A Day for a Lay: A Century of Gay Poetry. Ed. Gavin Geoffrey Dillard. New York: Barricade Books, 1999.
88 vol. 1 no. 1, December 2001
Ells S'Estimen: Poemes D'Amor Entre Homes. Ed. Lawrence Schimel. Barcelona: Llibres de l'Index, 1999
"Essay With Movable Parts: A Prose Poem by David Trinidad." Normal, IL: Thorngate Road, 1998.
Flanagan, Bob. Fuck Journal. New York: Hanuman Books, 1987.
Goldin, Nan. The Other Side. New York: Scalo Publishers, 1993.
Good Foot no. 1, Spring 2001.
The Hat. no. 3, Winter 1999-2000
Identity Lessons: Contemporary Writing About Learning to Be American. Ed. Maria Mazziotti Gillan and Jennifer Gillan. New York: Penguin, 1999.
The James White Review. vol. 17, no. 2, Spring 2000.
The James White Review. vol. 18, no. 1 and 2, Winter/Spring 2001.
Journal of Literature and Aesthetics. vol. 1, no. 1. July-December 2001.
The KGB Bar Book of Poems. Ed. David Lehman and Star Black. New York: Harper Collins, 2000.
LIT. no. 2 Winter 2000
The Literary Review. Vol 42. No 2. Winter 1999.
Matrix. mp/ 61
Mirage/Period(ical) no. 90, December 1999
The Outlaw Bible of American Poetry. Ed. Alan Kauman. New York: Thunder's Mouth Press, 1999.
Pearl no. 29, Fall/Winter 2000.
Plasticville. Chappaqua: Turtle Point Press, 2000.
Poetry for Dummies. Eds/ The Poetry Center, John Timpane, Maureen Watts. New York: Hungry Minds, 2001.
Poetry Project Newsletter. No. 176. October/November 1999.
Pressed Wafer. Eds. David Trinidad and Elaine Equi. NO. 2, March 2001.
Real Things: An Anthology of Popular Culture In American Poetry. Ed. Jim Elledge and Susan Swarwout. Bloomington and Indianapolis: Indiana University Press, 1999.
Stanford, Ann. Holding Our Own: The Selected Poems of Ann Stanford. Ed. Maxine Scates and David Trinidad. Port Townsend, Washington: Copper Canyon Press, 2001.
Stanford, Ann. Holding Our Own: The Selected Poems of Ann Stanford. Uncorrected Proof. Ed. Maxine Scates and David Trinidad. Port Townsend, Washington: Copper Canyon Press, 2001.
Tin House Magazine. vol. 2, no. 2, Winter 2001.
Urbanus Magazine. Summer 1999
Word of Mouth: An Anthology of Gay Poetry. ed. Timothy Liu. Jersey city, NJ: Talisman Press, 2000.
The World. no. 56/67, 2000.
The World in US; Lesbian and Gay Poetry of the Next Wave. Ed. Michael Lassell and Elena Gergiou. New York: St Martin's Press, 2000.
Accretions 2005
Missing Title
Columbia Poetry Review. no. 19, Spring 2006.
Court Green. no. 3, 2006.
Phoebe 2002: An Essay in Verse. by Jeffery Conway, Lynn Crosbie, and David Trinidad. 2003
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from David Trinidad, July 2000. The accession numbers associated with this purchase are 2006.106, 2001.106, and 2006.106
Diaries; Reviews (document genre); Avant-garde (Aesthetics); Sound recordings.; Literature, Experimental.; Posters.; Gays' writings, American.; Gay men |x Poetry.; Correspondence.; Los Angeles (Calif.); Magazines (Periodicals); Chicago (Ill.); Artists and community -- United States; Scrapbooks.; American literature -- 20th century.; Videocassettes.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; New York (N.Y.) -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; New York (N.Y.).; Authors, American -- 20th century.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Announcements.; Downtown writers.; Dlugos, Tim; Conway, Jeffery; Cooper, Dennis, 1953-; Beyond Baroque Literary Arts Center; Brainard, Joe, 1942-1994; Equi, Elaine; Gerstler, Amy; Crosbie, Lynn, 1963-; Tillman, Lynne; Killian, Kevin; Stanford, Ann; Wheeler, Susan, 1955-; Welt, Bernard, 1952-
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries A: General Correspondence 1970-1998
    - ABBOTT, STEVE. 3 letters, 1 postcard; ca. 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - ACKER, KATHY. 1 postcard; dated 1992. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ADAMS, STEPHEN J. 2 letters, 2 emails; dated 1996-1998. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AREVALO, PAUL. 1 letter; dated 1985. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - BARTEL, DENNIS. 1 letter; dated 1978. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - BEAUMONT, JEANNE MARIE. 3 letters, 3 postcards, 7 cards, 7 emails; dated 1995-1998; plus 11 Barbie photographs. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - BEER, TOM. 1 letter, 1 card; dated 1998. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - BERKSON, BILL. 2 postcards; dated 1985-1990. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - BEYOND BAROQUE. Complete set (23) of Poetry News newsletters, 10/80-8/82., 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - BIALOSKY, KAY (elementary school teacher). 3 letters; dated 1977-1981. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - BIBBINS, MARK. 4 emails; dated 1998. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - BITTENCOURT, VIVIEN. 1 postcard; dated 1998. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - BLACK, SOPHIE CABOT. 2 letters, 1 card; dated 1994-1998. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - BOONE, BRUCE. 1 letter, 3 postcards; dated 1985-1991. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - BOYD, GREG. 17 letters; dated 1980-1992. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - BRAINARD, JOE. 7 letters, 10 postcards, 1 card; ca. 1986-1993; plus handwritten copy of "Jimmy Schuyler: A Portrait" (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - BRAINARD, JOE. "Letters to Joe Brainard from Jimmy Schuyler 1966-1990," 198-page photocopy inscribed copies of I Remember, More I Remember, More I Remember More, Bolinas Journal, and The Friendly Way; and copies of Some Drawings of Some Notes to Myself and The Cigarette Book [removed to Downtown Collection] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - BRITTON, DONALD. 1 letter, 1 postcard; dated 1981. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - CAHILL, RON. 12 letters, 18 postcards; dated 1988-1990. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - CAPPS, PATRICIA (Rachel Sherwood's mother). 25 letters; dated 1979-1985. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - CARD, MACGREGOR. 1 letter, 1 email; dated 1998. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - CAREY, TOM. 13 letters, 2 postcards; dated 1981-1993. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - CARLSON, KAREN. 15 letters, 9 postcards; ca. 1976-1985; plus 26 pages of poetry. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - CARR, ROBIN. 3 letters, 2 postcards, 6 emails; ca. 1986-1998. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - CHASE, CLIFFORD. 1 letter; dated 1995. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - CHERNOFF, MAXINE. 4 letters, 4 postcards; dated 1984-1997. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - CHRISTOPHER, NICHOLAS. 5 letters, 1 postcard; dated 1988-1993. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - CLARK, TOM. 1 letter; ca. 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - CODRESCU, ANDREI. 3 letters; dated 1987-1994. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - COHEN, MARC. 1 postcard; dated 1996. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - CONLEY, DIANNE. 2 letters, 1 postcard, 4 emails; dated 1996-1998. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - CONWAY, JEFFERY. 41 letters, 12 postcards, 2 cards, 1 email; dated 1988 -1998; plus 15 pages of poetry; and inscribed copy of Blood Poisoning. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - COOPER, BERNARD. 2 cards, 4 emails; dated 1997-1998. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - COOPER, DENNIS. 22 letters, 12 postcards; dated 1979-1996; plus 10 pages of poetry; 1982 Christmas card (with photos of boys). (Box 1, Folder 34)